A Guide to Records of the Policy Office: Subject Files of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1983-1994 (bulk 1990-1993)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Records of the Policy Office: Subject Files of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder, 1983-1994 (bulk 1990-1994)
The Library of Virginia
35539
16.8 cu. ft. (48 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1990-1994: Wilder)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected and confidential information is restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78, 2.2-3800, and 2.2-3705.1-8. Types of previous restricted information may include, but are not limited to: privacy protected information and attorney-client privileged material.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder on October 31, 1996.
Biographical Information
Lawrence Douglas Wilder was born in Richmond, Va., on January 17, 1931. He graduated from Virginia Union University in 1951 and afterwards was drafted into the Army, where he served in the Korean War from 1952-1953 and received a bronze star. He then attended the Howard University School of Law and graduated in 1959. Douglas Wilder was elected to the Virginia Senate in 1969 as the first African American member since Reconstruction and served in the Senate for five terms. In 1985, he was elected to the office of Lieutenant Governor as the first African American to be elected to statewide office in Virginia. L. Douglas Wilder won the election for Governor of Virginia in 1989 and served from January 13, 1990 to January 14, 1994. He was the first African American to be elected as Governor in United States.
The Policy Office is a division of the Office of the Governor in the Executive Branch of Virginia state Government. During the Wilder Administration, the Policy Office was headed by Walter McFarlane, Executive Assistant for Policy, and four Special Assistants: Richard Taylor (Health and Human Resources, and Education), Robert Blue (Finance and Natural Resources), Jeff Nuechterlein (Economic Development and Transportation), and Lynne Porfiri (Administration and Public Safety). The Policy Office was responsible for review and coordination of all policy matters, including: review of proposed legislation from agencies and Cabinet; formulation of the Governor's legislative initiatives; tracking legislation and serving as legislative liaison; review of General Assembly approved legislation submitted to the Governor for signature, amendment or veto; review of death penalty clemency requests, as well as other pardon and restoration of rights requests; review of legal settlements and other legal matters from the Office of the Attorney General's Office; review of proposed regulations; review of all matters pertaining to the judiciary and writs of habeas corpus; review of proposed executive orders; assistance with speech writing; serving as staff for Governor's special commissions; administrative support for Governor's Fellows program; serving as special interest liaison; acting as in-house counsel; and all correspondence with policy implications or pertaining to sensitive or controversial issues requiring legal overview.
Scope and Content
Records of the Policy Office: Subject Files, 1983-1994, during the administration of Governor Lawrence Douglas Wilder. The collection is housed in 48 boxes and includes agendas, briefings, brochures, clippings, contracts, correspondence, financial statements, itineraries, maps, memorandum, newsletters, notes, photographs, programs, publications, reports, and other documents. The collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
A number of records relate to the unsuccessful effort by Jack Kent Cooke, then owner of the Washington Redskins football team, to push for the construction of a new football stadium in the Potomac Yard area of Alexandria. The area in question had been a railyard owned by the Richmond, Fredericksburg and Potomac Railroad (RF&P) before it was decommissioned in 1989, opening the site to potential development. The records for the potential stadium deal include surveys, plans, zoning ordinances, and reports. The deal was scrapped in October 1992, and the Washington football stadium was instead built in Prince George's County, MD.
Other topics include the expansion efforts of Virginia Commonwealth University in the Oregon Hill neighbordhood of Richmond; the state drug and alcohol policy, including a number of studies and reports; issues related to the legislative redistricting process that followed the 1990 census, including the creation of an 11th congressional district; the creation and efforts of the 21st Century Commission on African American Males, a national effort to focus national attention on issues facing black males and develop a set of public-policy recommendations and strategies for action; the institution of Project Streamline, an effort to consolidate and simplify management and work processes in state government, improving productivity and effeciency; the Gulf War and potential energy shortages; the National Air and Space Museum; and sole source procurements and contracts.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
Contents List
- Abortion, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Abortion, (Publication), Our Daughters' Decisions, The Conflict in State Law and Other Issues, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Accomplishments, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Acupuncture Society of Virginia, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Administrative Law Index, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Administrative Procedures Policies, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Administrative Process Act Amendments, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Administrative Process Registrar of Regulations, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Administrative Process - Regulations, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Aeroscience Institute Foundation, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- AFL-CIO, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- African Trade Conference, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- African Trade Trip, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Agency Head Performance Appraisals, Secretary of Education, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Agency Head Performance Appraisals, Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 1988-1989 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Agency Head Performance Appraisals, Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 1988-1989 (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Agendas and Initiatives, Draft Documents, 1990 (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Agendas and Initiatives, Draft Documents, 1990 (2 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Agendas and Initiatives, Draft Documents, 1990 (3 of 3) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Agendas and Initiatives, Final Reports, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Air and Space Museum (National), 1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Air and Space Museum (National), 1990 Jan.-Mar. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Air and Space Museum (National) 1990 Apr.-June (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Air and Space Museum (National), Legislative Strategy Session, 1990 May 15 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Air and Space Museum (National), Smithsonian Correspondence and Memos, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Air and Space Museum, Smithsonian, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Ambulance Authority, City of Richmond, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- American Bar Association, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- American Bar Association Study, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- American Council on Germany, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- American Ex-Prisoners of War, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Animal Rights, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, 1990 (Box 52, Folder 1)
- Appalachian Regional Commission, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Appalachian Regional Commission Meeting, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Appointments, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Appointments, Board of Visitors - Longwood College, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Appointments, Employee Advisory Committee, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Appointment with Bernard Simeon, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Arkansas vs. Virginia, Comparison, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Automation Research System Limited, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Barrett Learning Center, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Bell Atlantic Telephone Co., 1991 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- BFI Landfill, King and Queen County, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Biennial Report of Virginia Board of Examiners, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Billingon, Michael, Jr., 1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Black History Museum and Cultural Center of Va., Inc., 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Black Women United for Action (Mount Vernon Slave Memorial), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Board of Innovative Technology Authority, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Bond Issues, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Budget, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Budget Comparison, 1990-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Budget Speeches 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- C & P Telephone Company (TriCon Financing Proposal), 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Campaign Promises, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Capital Sentences/Executions, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Census, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Center for America's First Freedom, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Center for Public Services, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Challenger Center for Space Science Education, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Chesterfield School Foreign Language Program, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Children, V.A. Treatment Center, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Christening of Aircraft Carrier, George Washington CVN 73-Program Newport News Shipbuilding, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Clean Indoor Air, 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Collective Bargaining, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- College vs. Private Business, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Columbus Crossing, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- COMAND (Commonwealth's Offensive Mobilization Against Narcotic Distribution) Task Force, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Commission on Bicentennial of U.S. Constitution, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Commission on Equity in Public Education, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Concurrent Jurisdiction, Deed of Cessation, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Condemnation, Sec. of Transportation John G. Milliken, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Conflict of Interest, 1990-1993 (Box 52, Folder 2)
- Conflict of Interest, 1992 (Box 52, Folder 3)
- Conflict of Interest, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Congressional Delegation Meeting, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Congressional Special Unemployment Compensation Benefits Bill, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Constitutional Issues - Budget, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Construction Control Services Corporation, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Containerized Cargo, Special Session, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Continuing Legal Education, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Crime Victims Compensation, Federal Applications, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Crime Victims Compensation Payments (Certifications), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Defense Department (U.S.), 1991 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Defense Secretaries Conference, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Democratic Governor's Association, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Democratic National Committee Resolutions, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Democratic Party of Virginia, General Assembly Democratic Perspective, 1983-1985 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Democratic Party of Virginia, General Assembly Democratic Perspective, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Democratic Party of Virginia, Perspective, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Desert Storm/Shield (Federal Executive Order), 1991 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Desrochers, Paul (Desrochers v. Diamond), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Direct Share Program Guidelines, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Disabled Community, 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Driver's Licenses Revocation, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Drug Free Work Place, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Drug Press Conference, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Drug Programs, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Dues Check Off (Payroll Deductions for State Employee Association), 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Dulles Corridor Rail System, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Eastern Bloc Trip Proposal, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Ecology, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Electric Chair Availability, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Elliott, Archie, III, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Environmental Racism, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Escheats East Land Developers Lot, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- European Trade Mission, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Executive Order Delegation of Authority Draft, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Executive Order 35-91, Authority and Responsibilities of Secretariats, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Executive Services, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Exporting - Snydor, Linda, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Extradition Request - John Wilson Sturgill, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Fall Creek Interceptor Sewer Line Extension, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Family and Children's Trust Fund of Virginia, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Fastship Working Group, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Federal Contracts Update, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Federal Excise Tax on Distilled Spirits (Potential), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Federal Executive Order on Civil Justice Reform, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Federal Jurisdiction, Acceptance of Concurrent, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Federal Legislation, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Federal Legislative Priorities, 1991-1992 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Federal Legislative Priorities, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Film Office - Location of Filming for "A Woman Named Jackie," 1991 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Film Office - National Rifle Association Commercial, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Films, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Financial Disclosure, 1993 (Box 52, Folder 4)
- Financial Disclosure, Governor Wilder, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Financial Statement, Office of the Governor, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Financing of Literacy Fund School Construction Projects Biennium, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 29)
- FOIA (Freedom of Information Act), 1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- FOIA - Dept. of Military Affairs, 1992 (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 2)
- FOIA - Dept. of Military Affairs, 1992 (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 3)
- FOIA General Requests, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- FOIA General Requests, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- FOIA General Requests, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- FOIA Request - Committee Minutes, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- FOIA Request - Dept. of Military Affairs, African Head of State Summit, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- FOIA Requests - Helicopters, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- FOIA Request - Honorarium Trips, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- FOIA Request - Human Rights Council, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- FOIA Request - Inaugural Invitations, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- FOIA Request - Journal Papers, I-95, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- FOIA Request - McSweety, Burtch, and Crump, Cost of Regular and Special Assembly Sessions, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- FOIA Request - Telephone Bills, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- FOIA Request - Virginia Retirement Supplemental System, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Gay Alliance, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- General Assembly Update, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- General Assembly, Abandoned Facilities, Draft Legislation, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- General Assembly, Amending Call to Assembly, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- General Assembly, Amendment Administrative Process Act, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- General Assembly, Appropriations Bill, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- General Assembly, Arlington County - Legislative Package, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- General Assembly, Continuing Legal Education, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- General Assembly, Constitutional Issues - Budget, 1991 (1 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 19)
- General Assembly, Constitutional Issues - Budget, 1991 (2 of 2) (Box 10, Folder 20)
- General Assembly, DUI-DWI Laws, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- General Assembly, Executive Legislative Package, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- General Assembly, Executive Mansion Chimney Repairs, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- General Assembly, Executive Mansion Use, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- General Assembly, HJR 448 - Obstacles Facing Businesses, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- General Assembly, House Bill 808 - Augmented Estate Legislation, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- General Assembly, Intern Program, 1989-1991 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- General Assembly, Innovations Awards, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- General Assembly, Iraq 1991 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- General Assembly, Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC), 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- General Assembly, Kucharski Report (Pay Irregularities Status), 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- General Assembly, Law Day, 1991-1992 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- General Assembly, Legislative Issues Possible (Outgoing Correspondence), 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- General Assembly, Legislative Proposals, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- General Assembly, Legislative Session Cost, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- General Assembly, Lincoln Mercury (Limo Service), 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- General Assembly, Lobbyist, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- General Assembly, National Association of Sheriffs, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- General Assembly, Primaries, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- General Assembly, Reorganization Plan, Governor's, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- General Assembly, Report: Interim Financing Alternatives for Capital Projects, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- General Assembly, Report: Review of the Virginia Department of Workers' Compensation, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- General Assembly, Report: Statewide Staffing Standards for Funding of Commonwealth's Attorneys, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- General Assembly, Secretary of Transportation Proposed Legislation, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- General Assembly, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- General Assembly, Auditing of Constitutional Offices, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- General Assembly, Bond Bills, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- General Assembly, Budget General, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- General Assembly, Early Release of Non-Violent Inmates, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- General Assembly, Economic and Revenue Forecast for Fiscal Year, 1992-1994 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- General Assembly, Ethics Reform Campaign, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- General Assembly, Financial Condition of Commonwealth (Fiscal Year), 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- General Assembly, Gun Trafficking in Virginia, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- General Assembly, House Bills, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- General Assembly, Legislation, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- General Assembly, Pre-Session Legislative Process, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- General Assembly, Private Security Industry Regulations, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- General Assembly, Special Advice Given to the Governor, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- General Assembly, Ethics Commission, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- General Assembly, Federal Legislative Priorities, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- General Assembly, Fines Amnesty Program Report of Supreme Court of Virginia, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- General Assembly, Governor's Legislative Package, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
- General Assembly, House Resolution 2848 (Interstate Waste Legislation), 1993 (Box 12, Folder 19)
- General Assembly, Interns, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 20)
- General Assembly, Judges, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 21)
- General Assembly, Legislation, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 22)
- General Assembly, Norplant, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 23)
- General Assembly, Report: Committee on District Court Examining the Feasibility of an Alternative Method for Disposing of Traffic Infractions, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 24)
- General Assembly, Resolutions Involving the Governor, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 25)
- General Assembly, Revised Economic Revenue Forecasts, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- General Assembly, Senate Joint Resolution, 1992-1993 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- General Assembly, Senate Session, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- General Assembly, Tec-9 Weapons, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- General Assembly, Vehicle Emissions Programs, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- General Assembly, Violent Crime Initiatives, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- General Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- General Correspondence, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- General Correspondence (William Porter), 1992 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- General Fund Revenue, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- George Mason Memorial Society, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Gideon's Bible, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Gideon Missionary Baptist Fellowship, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Governor's Budget - General Fund Reductions, 1990-1992 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Governor's Commission on Campaign Finance Reform Government Accountability and Ethics, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Governor's Daily Travel Narrative Itinerary, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Governor's Decision on Proposed Legislation - Public Safety, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Governor's Symposium on Virginia's Economic and Budget Outlook, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Governor's Working Schedule, 1991-1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Grandville P. Meade Scholarship Trust, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Grange, Jorman, Deptuy Chief of Staff, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Greenwood Partnership, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Grievance, Robert C. Smith, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Hall and Tillett Report, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Hatch Art Issues, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Haymore, Glenn D., Jr., 1994 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Haymore, Glenn D., Jr., Chronology of Events, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Health Issues, 1989-1992 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Helicopter, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Homeless, Virginia Coalition for the Homeless, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 14)
- House and Senate Finance Appropriations Committee, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 15)
- Hurricane Emily, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Inaugural Committee vs. Joyce International Inc. and Joyce Office Products, June-Sept. 1990 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Inaugural Committee vs. Joyce International Inc. and Joyce Office Products, Oct.-Nov. 1990 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Inaugural Committee vs. Joyce International Inc. and Joyce Office Products, Dec. 1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Inaugural Committee vs. Joyce International Inc. and Joyce Office Products, Jan.-Feb. 1991 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Inaugural Committee vs. Joyce International Inc. and Joyce Office Products, Invoices, 1990-1991 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Inmate Threats, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Innovative Technology, Center for, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Interns, Governor's Office, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Investor Concerns, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Invitations From Head of State, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Iraq, Day of Appreciation for Veteran of the Gulf War and Their Families, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Iraq - Energy Plans, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Iraq - Energy Savings, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Iraq - Gas Rationing and Price Control, 1981-1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Iraq - Kuwait, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Iraq - Media Questions, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Iraq - Oil Crisis, 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Iraq - Operation Desert Storm, 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- JLARC Administrative Process Act, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- J. Monroe hite Law License Reinstatement Request, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- J.T. Shropshire, Chief of Staff Memorandum and Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Judicial Court Vacancy, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 12)
- King Commission (Federal Holiday), Martin Luther King, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 13)
- Kwanza, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- Labor Dispute, Greyhound Bus Strike, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Labor Dispute, Mining, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Lafayette Soccer Tournament, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Lake Gaston Pipeline Project, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- LaRouche, Lyndon H., 1986-1993 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Law Week and Law Day Certificate of Recognition, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Legal Assistant Committee, 1989-1990 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Legal Assistants Week (Virginia, Certificate of Recognition), 1990 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Legion Design/Campbell and Associates Chartered Engineering Firm, 1985-1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Legislative Concerns, 1990-1993 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Legislative Services, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Legislative Session, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Legislative Session, Appointments Issue, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Legislative Session, August County, Rep. Request for Special Session, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 9)